

Summary _

Deep Learning Researcher

GOOGLE SCHOLAR

I'm currently a PhD candidate student at Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences, affiliated with National Laboratory of Pattern Recognition and supervised by Professor Kaiqi Huang. I work on image processing, computer vision and deep learning. My research interests are pixel-level image understanding, geometric deep learning and network architecture design.

Research Experience _____

Palmwin Information Technology

Nanjing, China

RESEARCHER

Aug. 2015 - Oct. 2015

- Website: http://www.chatgame.me/en/
- Write a survey on SLAM and AR.

NLPR (National Laboratory of Pattern Recognition)

Beijing, China

RESEARCHER

Dec. 2014 - Apr. 2015

- Website: http://www.nlpr.ia.ac.cn/nlpren/EN/volumn/home.shtml
- Design and implement a car recognition system with 95% accuracy based on CNNs.

Education

CASIA (Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences)

Beijing, China

PHD IN COMPUTER VISION AND DEEP LEARNING

Sep. 2015 - Present

Topic: Pixel-level vision understanding GPA: **3.67**/4

NJU (Nanjing University)

Nanjing, China

B.S. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Sep. 2011 - Jun. 2015

Thesis: Deep Active Learning GPA: **3.87**/4 Rank: **5**/257

Publications _

Fast End-to-End Trainable Guided Filter

Project Website

HUIKAI WU, SHUAI ZHENG, JUNGE ZHANG, KAIQI HUANG

IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2018

A2-RL: Aesthetics Aware Reinforcement Learning for Image Cropping

Project Website

Debang Li, **Huikai Wu**, Junge Zhang, Kaiqi Huang

IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2018

MSC: A Dataset for Macro-Management in StarCraft II

Project Website

HUIKAI WU, JUNGE ZHANG, KAIQI HUANG

arXiv preprint arXiv:1710.03131

GP-GAN: Towards Realistic High-Resolution Image Blending

Project Website

HUIKAI WU, SHUAI ZHENG, JUNGE ZHANG, KAIQI HUANG

arXiv preprint arXiv:1703.07195

Highlighted Research Experience _____

Fast End-to-End Trainable Guided Filter

PROJECT WEBSITE (TO BE APPEARED IN CVPR 2018)

We present a deep learning block for joint upsampling, which aims at generating high-resolution output. With the proposed block, we achieve the state-of-the-art performance and run 10-100 times faster. The proposed block can be widely deployed in dense prediction tasks ranging from image processing to computer vision. The technique report is published in CVPR 2018.

A2-RL: Aesthetics Aware Reinforcement Learning for Image Cropping

PROJECT WEBSITE (TO BE APPEARED IN CVPR 2018)

We formulate image cropping task as a sequential decision-making process and propose an algorithm based on deep reinforcement learning. The proposed algorithm achieves the state-of-the-art performance with much fewer candidate windows and much less time. The technique report is published in CVPR 2018.

GP-GAN: Towards Realistic High-Resolution Image Blending

PROJECT WEBSITE

We propose GP-GAN for image blending task, which is a framework combining the strengths of gradient-based image editing and GANs. The proposed approach can deliver high-resolution, realistic images with fewer bleedings and unpleasant artifacts.

Honors & Awards _____

INTERNATIONAL

2017 **4th Place**, StarCraft Competition in AIIDE 2017, beat Facebook's team.

DOMESTIC

2016 **1st Place**, CCF Big Data Competition: Movie Box Prediction.

Project _____

Face Swap Jan. 2018

PROJECT WEBSITE

Swap face between two photos with Python 3, OpenCV and dlib.

MSC: A Dataset for Macro-Management in StarCraft II

Sep. 2017

PROJECT WEBSITE

A dataset for macro-management in StarCraft II based on PySC2.

Chainer implementation of Pix2Pix

Mar. 2017

PROJECT WEBSITE

Chainer implementation of Image-to-Image Translation Using Conditional Adversarial Networks

Chainer version of neural-style and fast-neural-style

Mar. 2017

Project Website

Chainer implementation of A Neural Algorithm of Artistic Style and Perceptual Losses for Real-Time Style Transfer and Super-Resolution

Chainer implementation of realismCNN

Mar. 2017

PROJECT WEBSITE

 $Chainer\ implementation\ of\ realism CNN\ proposed\ in\ \textit{Learning\ a\ Discriminative\ Model\ for\ the\ Perception\ of\ Realism\ in\ Composite\ Images$

References _____

Prof. Kaiqi Huang

Homepage E-mail:kqhuang@nlpr.ia.ac.cn

National Lab. of Pattern Recognition, Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Science

Prof. Junge Zhang

HOMEPAGE E-mail: jgzhang@nlpr.ia.ac.cn

National Lab. of Pattern Recognition, Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Science

Dr. ShuaiZheng

Homepage E-mail: szhengcvpr@gmail.com

Research Scientist, eBay Al, San Francisco, CA, US